All right, holding meeting to order at 5.34, 4.34, sorry. Roll call, please. Yes, Commissioner Genvilla. Here. Commissioner Foley. Present. Commissioner Hollien. Here. Commissioner Lister. Here. Commissioner Malongo-Zapata. Pledges.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of the United States of America, and to the republic for which it stands, one nation, under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all. Thank you. Approval of minutes. Oh, sorry. I just want her to see that her request was fulfilled. Oh, snacks.
Approval of minutes. Minutes of June 15, 2022. Motion to accept the minutes. All in favor? Aye. Motion passes. Financial? So the financial
Our agency-wide statements that you have in your board packet reflect eight months of our fiscal year. So it's a period ending May 31st, 2022. And the addition to the reserves at this point is $934,439. And that's an agency-wide surplus.
Okay. Can I get a motion to accept financial reports? So moved. Second. All in favor? Aye. Motion passed, thank you. Public input? No. Yeah, number five. You didn't include the...
Yes, I didn't see that. Okay. What do you need? Is Markham separate? Markham is under the executive group. Oh, okay. All right. I thought that was going to be in the financials. Okay. Oh, sorry. It's okay. Sorry about that. Okay. No, we're good. All right. Public input. Open. Yes. Yes, I'm here. If people are looking at 15 Canal Street, there was an announcement recently
storage units will be completely removed, permanently removed after there's some modification, I guess, for a new energy system or something like this. So, a tenant in the building, her name's Kate Ryan, she wrote a letter and about six of us signed it. It's in her- Can you ask his name for the record? Yeah, what is your name? I'm sorry. Matthew Paige Lieberman. Yeah, Matthew Paige Lieberman. Thank you.
Can that be read out loud into the record? I'm gonna pass it on.
Thank you, Matthew. So with him making a request for it to be read, so it can be read, can you do that? I will, I will, yeah. After everyone read it and I'll read it out loud. So it will be recorded.
Do you want to read the second one? It's pausing? No, not yet. And then I'll read it.
Can I help you?
I'll make a note to the board that that's addressed to me it's the first time I've seen this. Okay.
All right, here we go. I was reading July 9th, 2022. Dear Jeffrey Driscoll, so this is the first time you're getting this, so. I've not seen it, but I can address it. All right, let me read it. Read it while it's on there. Okay, yeah. Yeah. It's fine. Dear Jeffrey Driscoll and the Medford Housing Authority Board of Commissioners, hello, we are tenants of the Medford Housing Authority Phillip Building located at 15 Canal Street.
We are writing to respectfully ask that you please not remove the storage spaces in the basement permanently. Although not everyone who lives in a building uses the storage space, for those who do, it is essential. We use the storage spaces for ordinary things that we wish to keep, but which do not fit into our apartments, such as air conditioners, beach chairs, and Christmas decorations.
For many people, this building is a stop on the road to other places, such as Section 8, moving in with family or getting a job and moving out of public housing completely.
There are things which may fit into other parts of our lives that do not fit into our current lives, and we would like to save them. Because everyone here has a low income, however, we are not able to afford a conventional storage unit, nor is it feasible when our storage needs are adequately served by the small space in the basement. We are asking
that you please reconsider cutting off our access to storage space in the basement. Even a smaller space will be better than nothing. The current space are kept clean, and I have never seen vermin there. They are easily accessible when we want to do things like put up our Christmas tree. They are very small things, but they have a great value to numerous people
and you will be doing a wonderful good deed by continuing allowing us to access some storage. Thank you very much for your time and attention. And it is signed by Kate Ryan, Beth Onafiri, I think I'm saying that right, Amy Walsh, Daniel Scarfield,
Mr. Lieberman, apartment 15, and someone else. I can't read this. Thank you for coming. Matthew and I have participated in a number of housing forums and I always respect what you have to say and I appreciate the
vantage point that you come from in so far as being one of our residents. I wish you would have brought that to me. You could have brought that to me. The only inquiry that I have received concerning this, I have not received an inquiry from any of the residents. The only inquiry I've received was from a city councilor who was contacted and who contacted me.
And the response that I provided to that city councilor was a response that I received from maintenance who had requested that those storage areas be removed. They described them to me as three foot by three foot by four foot deep. We had a similar issue when we were
dealing with the storage areas at Walkland Court. And I'm sure, Losa, you'll remember that because you were on the board at that point in time when we had to remove those storage facilities also. But they tell me there's three reasons. One is that there was excess storage there that hadn't been taken out based upon people leaving and not emptying out their storage. Not a big problem. Two, that because of the storage that was there, even though I know Matthew in his letter indicated that he had not seen any
Any vermin I think is the word that was used. The maintenance management tells me that there were mice infestation that had gone on there. Again, something that we certainly can take care of. But lastly is the fact that that now is going to become an electrical room.
And that is, as I understand it, part of that is due to the $1.6 million upgrade of the security system. And so that's what the purpose of that is. Matthew, I'll present to you right now that if for some reason that entire area isn't used for the purpose of being an electrical room, I'd certainly consider there being some storage. The difficulty with that site, though, is that
There's no other area that lends itself to that, not that I'm aware of. So, that's my answer to the board. Matthew. Yeah, just to clarify, this is not my letter. I'm representing Kate Ryan. She cannot be here for medical reasons. But yeah, I'm aware she reached out to Nicole, Nicole, City Council President. Nicole reached out to you. My understanding is that Nicole and her doctor,
Nicole called me, and I returned her call within less than 24 hours, and she and I spoke. When she got back to me just, what's today, Wednesday? Monday. Okay. All right. And then I know that Kate also reached out to our building manager, who I think just said something effective. Yeah, it's like a decision from higher up. And I apologize if I didn't follow the correct procedure of bringing it to the board.
I would have saved you the trouble of doing that, and I would have explained this to you. It would have been the same explanation, and I'm accessible. But the process is that if you're not satisfied with, or you said Kate Ryan, if she's not satisfied with the answer she got from the manager, then she should deal with Jennifer McNabb. If she's not satisfied with Jennifer, then she can come to me. If she's not satisfied with me, then she can come to the board.
My point being is we would have been able to resolve this back on July 9th, I believe. Yeah, July 9th. Yeah, July 9th. Yeah, I remember I was here a few years ago. I remember there was a woman who brought an issue to here and you were talking about the proper chain of command. I think perhaps one issue is, I think a lot of us aren't familiar. That's not specified.
And I know that from this letter, you clarified that it's going to be completely utilized for this new electrical system. That's what's been represented to me. But that's not what's been communicated to the tenants. What's communicated in the letter we received is temporarily in order to install some things, but then the storage units would not be made available after any kind of modifications are made.
And those are to this degree that you've said that these units will continue to be available that are not, you know. If it's not an electrical room, I don't have a problem with the storage there. The two of the three issues that were presented to me are two issues that can be resolved. The third issue is the fact, and that's the main reason for the taking that over, is because of the need for an electrical room.
Okay, so I guess we won't know for a few months if there will perhaps be any spare units, right? That I don't know. I will tell you that they're beginning the installation of the security systems in one month. Originally, the architect, excuse me, yeah, I guess it was the architect or the engineer, had indicated that we would begin
at Canal Street. That seems to have changed today for some other reasons not related to Canal Street. You're saying that this installation will be happening in multiple buildings?
Multiple sites. Multiple sites. If there's availability of them. Okay. Does that satisfy you?
Yeah, I think that's along the lines of what I was hoping. I mean, I don't use an air conditioner, but I know a lot of people do. I think that her arguments are particularly salient rather than having a big air conditioner on the floor or something like this. Just so the board will know, Canal Street was basically a turnkey that was purchased a number of years ago. Not built for public housing. When you walk in, you either walk down or you walk up.
not built for the clientele that we have there. Matthew is certainly able to navigate those. Some of our residents are not. All right, thank you very much. Thank you all. Thanks, Matthew. Thank you. There's no, can I get a motion to close public input? So moved. Second. Thank you. All in favor? Aye. Thank you. So moved. Executive report.
Yeah, well, Michael, I won't keep Michael for too long. We have, on page 13, the financial report, the audit report from Markham, who are our auditors. They come in on an annual basis. They start this audit by contacting and reaching out to us in the late fall, early winter. They deal with us in particular with Michael and with Teresa Ewell.
over the course of the first six months of the year. And they have presented this to us. Their deadline, Michael, if I'm not mistaken, is June 30th, correct? That's correct. And they filed this with HUD as an independent audit. Happy to say, for the fifth year in a row, well, actually, let me see, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, yep, for five years in a row, we don't have any findings.
Kayleen I take that I see the smile so no findings we actually three years ago we had two findings we had two findings and we found that the auditors were wrong and they corrected it so that's even better than having no findings when you have findings and you tell the auditors that they made two mistakes so am I right on that Michael? Michael do you want to add anything from a financial point of view
No, not at all. You know, I guess the only thing that I'd like to add is that the Housing Authority had a net surplus, agency-wide surplus in 2021 of $1,711,084, and that's net operating. That doesn't include your depreciation. So generally, when you calculate out your net operating income or net operating surplus,
you know, you take out depreciation. So they had a housing authority had a surplus of $1,711,084 in 2021. Thank you, Michael. You're welcome.
continue with my executive director report yes it's very minimal I just wanted to make sure I'm not missing something it was this printed out just twice accidentally or was there a difference between these two I just want to make sure I wasn't like I was like reading the two of them and I'm like am I missing something is there a different date on these or something but
but thank you. So what you're saying is there's two in here? I didn't see two in here.
And I don't necessarily always provide that, but because we have three new members, I wanted to give you a copy of the audit report. You can digest it as comprehensively as you wish. But the point being was for you to understand that
We do have someone who comes in and goes over very thoroughly our books. And it's a credit to the staff and to Michael that we get through these things on a successful basis. They also look at not only the financials, but they look at programmatically procurement at public housing, leased housing, and things such as that. So it's a very thorough review.
I have a number of reports that I've given you. If you have any questions, I'd be more than happy to address those. We have been meeting with the residents.
here at Salton Stall. Every month we meet with all the residents at the various sites and I know that Gabe and Jeanette and Jennifer were out at Walkling this week. There's a policy here for or I should say a plan here that was presented to them. Gabe and I just met with a 3.30 this afternoon with an abutter to Walkling Court who had reached out to me and we're looking to do some
some work on the North Street side, the installation of some fencing there that we have from, we've got money from the opera program. That'll be very, he was really happy, said that he's been trying, he's been told for 10 years that he was going to get, that this was, the money was set aside, he said, 10 years ago, and he never saw it.
It was a very positive response. We continue to meet with Consigli, who is the construction manager for this site. We're in negotiation with Dietz, an architectural firm out of Springfield, for the walkway court project that the board awarded last board meeting, I believe.
And we've not yet executed a contract with them, but we're looking to try to negotiate that in order to move forward. So we move forward with that. It's a busy time. You know, the summer years ago, the summer used to slow down. The summer in December used to slow down. It doesn't happen anymore. We have a number of legal actions ongoing now. We did not previously during the pandemic
The last time that we were in a call with anyone was April of last year. There are approximately 11 actions underway at this point. There's no longer the ability for individuals to get funds from the state, unless they had received funds within the past six months, then they're protected, but most
A good portion of the actions going forward are for cause, not for non-payment. So I should use the two words, lease enforcement. It's for lease enforcement, so we're working with that. We continue to work closely with the police and for all of our sites, some sites more than others. But the police have been very helpful.
coordinating efforts with us. We did have a problem 4th of July, right Losa? Yeah. At LaPree. We have that on video. Unfortunately, the video that we have isn't as clear as we would like it. So that's why we're spending 1.6 million dollars to get an enhanced system. I'm sorry? Camera system. Yes, yeah, enhanced system.
Michael, is there anything else from a financial point of view that I've skimmed over? No, that's all. Michael and I, along with Teresa and the staff, are developing the budget and Michael and Teresa have been very helpful recently in, I shouldn't say recently like you haven't been before, but in recent discussions with
the folks from Cambridge as far as the budget for soft install, which originally was in the vicinity of just over 120 million for construction purposes, 150 million overall. That's some place in the vicinity now of around 102 million, maybe 104 million in that area, so we've reduced it by about $20 million.
So the value, you guys would know this better than I, the value engineering, I believe it's called, which is what we're in the process of doing now to see where we proceed forward. And lastly is the fact that we've had some turnover in staff.
We've had a few folks who have, three folks in particular, who have handed in their resignation and have left over the last two weeks or are leaving within the next few days for other opportunities by their choice. So we have a number of openings. Barbara is advertising for us and
Barbara, I would have to venture to say that we seem to be on the average, sometimes we get nine a day, sometimes we get two a day, but on the average we're probably getting around five or six resumes a day that we're reviewing. And the process that I follow is that the folks who are going to be immediate supervisors are the ones who do the initial interview. If they find that they have candidates that are favorable and satisfactory to them, then they refer them to me and then I interview them.
but we have maintenance positions available, we have administrative positions available at this point in time. Madam Chair? Is there anything else you'd like to add? That's it?
I think some folks may say that's more than enough. In reference to me, I'd like to add in reference to the July 4th incident that took place. I wish that there was more involvement with the people that responded. Unfortunately, that's not what happened. It was really chaotic down there.
We're hoping that in a future that's, you know, is better. It was fine, but yeah. Was it the issue with residents or other people? There was people from everywhere that actually happened to be in the, in the, there were over a hundred, over a hundred young adults and some youth.
that were there. The chair and I have had a discussion about that. I am aware that there's been significant follow-up. I immediately let him know when it happened.
I just wanted to, you know, like brought it out, you know, like something like that, you know. I'm glad you're taking care of it. Yeah, he, I'm able to contact him right away. Anything that happened, which is great. So I appreciate that, you know. All right. Can I get a motion to close the executive report, please? The security director report. Yeah, motion to close the executive report.
Can I get a second? Second. Thank you. Motion made and seconded by? Yeah. Okay, let's move on.
Do you still need Michael? No, we're all set. I just want to make sure. Did you get your signatures? Yeah, we're all set. Thank you, Michael. Do you still need me tomorrow? I'll email him later. Michael, do you still need Kayleen tomorrow? No, Jeff can sign the other ones. Michael, would you leave those by my door? Sure will. And I'll sign them tonight. Thank you.
All right, new business. Resolution number A, resolution number 2022-032. Notice of public hearing, DHCD annual plan FY 2023, consideration of the request by executive director to adapt resolution number 2022-033, approving the Medford Housing Authority's annual plan for fiscal year 2023 for state-aided public housing.
with certification by the Executive Director and subsequent submission of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts Department of Housing and Community Development. Madam Chair, this is an annual plan that we submit. Basically, we fill it in from DHCD. Part of this is from the review that the Housing Authority goes under every year.
When DHCD comes out and looks at the authority and looks at the authority's operational plans, in particular for maintenance, as I indicated, it's an annual plan that's submitted on a yearly basis. And a lot of this, Kayleen, I'm sure you do this in Lexington, a lot of this is just fill in the blanks from DHCD. But it is a formalized process that the board would
would need to approve this so that we can submit it. And the timeliness of today's meeting was in part because of this and one or two other things. Can I get a motion to approve resolution number 2022-032? I'll make that motion. I'll second that motion. All in favor? Aye. Thank you.
resolution number 2022-033, consideration of request by Executive Director to adopt resolution number 2022-034. It's actually 033. 033, that's what I thought. I made a note, thank you. 033 to approve the Medford Housing Authority's public FYB 2022 annual plan and subsequent submission to the U.S. Department of Housing and Harbor Development, which submission includes the following.
PHA certification of compliance with PHA plans and related regulation on board resolution to accompany the PHA plan. Civil rights certification and certification by state or local housing of PHA consistency with the consolidation plan executed by the mayor. Madam Chair? Yes. If I may, again, this is an annual plan. This is for HUD.
and it is similar to the state where the Housing Authority populates on the computer that which is directed by in this case HUD. The significance here is that within the context of this plan to some extent greater than with DHCD is our ability to indicate
more verbiage as far as what the authority is doing. And so, for example, two years ago before we had put in the plan,
for the soft install renovations to be undertaken, we needed to modify the plan because it wasn't within here. So we are required to follow what it is that's within this. Somewhat of a broad, there's some broad statements in here that allows us to operate, but HUD wants to ensure that we're following their mandate moving forward.
Can I get a motion on resolution 2022-033? I just want to say, under B2, where it says new activities and Medford housing is checked off every single box, I just think that's incredibly impressive. Reading that narrative, the work being done here is
just like there are leaps and bounds ahead of other agencies, or we are, I guess I should say. I just want to make that note. We. We. We. I'm glad to hear that. A lot of work. Thank you. It is. When reading through those things, you actually see. Yeah, like Lexi said, who knows? So, that's very impressive.
You know I give credit to the staff. Definitely. I give credit to the staff. You know we've got a very good staff and very very very hard-working. I know that I know that you see Barbara Vivian and I mean she exemplifies what we have here. There's a number of Barbara Vivians here. Yes. Can I say that? I'll make that motion. Is that okay to say that? To approve the resolution number 2022-033. Can I get a second please? I'll second that, yeah. Thank you. All in favor?
All right. Great, thanks. Resolution C. Resolution number 2022-034, consideration of proposed by Executive Director to approve an application for waiver from participation in DHCD's original capital assistance team program. Carrying on with what I just said a moment ago,
Because we're a small agency, as far as the state is concerned, with only 144 units, we are able to participate in the RCAT team, which is the Regional Capital Assistance Team program, where DHCD provides
expertise, if you may, in the procurement and oversight of construction projects. We waive out of it every year because Gabe is sufficiently qualified and capable of doing this, in fact, more so than most, if not all, other housing authorities. So we just need to officially have the board vote so that I can sign off on the waiver and submit that, not only the waiver itself, but submit a copy of your waiver.
Do you know who your RCAP would be? Is it Chelmsford? I think it's Chelmsford, yes. Yes. Which I know the gentleman, at least the gentleman who was there. I don't know if he's still there. Correct, yeah. Can I get a motion for resolution C? So moved. Second? Okay. 237. 237, 236. All right.
You need a second, right? Yes. Second. All in favor? Aye. Thank you.
Move along to D, resolution number 2022-035, consideration of request by executive director to approve a contract to Enterprise Equipment Co., Inc., of Weymouth, Massachusetts, for MHA job number 2114, M3, Weldon Gardens, roofing, gas, fire, makeup, air, unit replacement. The total amount of the contract is $207,706, including base and alternate.
Some, like, chuckles over there. So, I don't know what a fired makeup air unit is. Anybody? What it does?
It's my understanding, and two board members with more experience in this than I may correct me, but it's my understanding that this is for the common areas? Make it be a unit. It takes in outside air and it creates fresh air. You can use it for fresh air for like common areas or
A lot of times they'll pump fresh air into a residential apartment building or something like that. But most commonly, these are probably, they're gas-fired, so they're probably just heating only, and they're probably just heat for common areas in the building. That's what I'm assuming. It's almost like we cycle the air back. Yeah. They're gas-fired, so they've just got to be heated. If they had any type of piping to them, they could be dual. They could have condensed water, but I don't think that's the case. My understanding, Paul, I could be mistaken on this too, though, but we have had issues. Yeah, it is two.
They're up on the roof. And we actually, a few years back, we had budgeted $100,000 for this, $50,000 per unit. I was a little bit taken, not a little bit, I was a lot taken back by the price that came in. But everything is more expensive today. Are you going to be even more taken back by the lead time on the things because they're probably never going to get them?
You probably won't see these things for 26 months. If these are things that just went down now and they've got to be ordered now, I'd be shocked if they're going to get them any time soon. They're on their way out. They're on their way out. They're still operational. We've put Band-Aids on them. I don't know what type of units they were. I'll just say that they're just gas-fired make-up air units. I don't know what type of brand they're buying. It doesn't matter. Whatever.
You might see that. I guess if I went to the link on the bid form, it says view bids, I don't know. You'd see it there. You'd see what they're, yeah. Either way. Okay. Can I get a motion for that if there's no more discussion? So we're including the alternate, right? Yes. It's including both. Base and alternate.
Yes. I'll make that motion. What is it? That she was questioning about the base and the alternate on that motion. Oh, okay. Okay. All right. I'll second it. All right. All in favor? A roll call? A roll call. Commissioner Eugenia? Yes. Commissioner Foley? Yes. Commissioner Holien? Yes. Commissioner Lister? Yes. Thank you. All right.
resolution number 2022-036, consideration of request by executive director to approve a contract to Egan Builders of Winchester, Massachusetts for MHA job number 2001, M1, Willis Ave, 20 Exchange Avenue, rehabilitation of fire damage unit. The total amount of the contract is $259,000.
This is a five-minute chair. Yes. This is a unit that quit fire in November. And we've had an architect out there to take a look at it to do some preliminary designs and assisted with the preparation of the bid. The low bid came in at $279.
We've used HE in the past. They have been successful in the work they've done for us. I'm just, I was just astounded at the high price that this was. It's a three bedroom unit that caught fire. One of the bedrooms caught fire. But really the biggest issue was the water damage that was caused.
by the fire department. I shouldn't say caused by the fire department, but as a result of putting the fire out. It started with the overheating of a multi-plug and there was some electronic toy, a box that would connect up to a TV that was left on a bed. So I'm not sure if it was the
the overheating from the multi-plug, even though the fire department did indicate that on the scene, or if it was because of what was plugged into it was put on a bed. It generates the heat from the mattress. Do you know at the top of your head what the estimate was? Like in the bid? I just wondering how much over it is. We anticipated it was going to be in the vicinity of around $200,000.
And I don't know where that number came from, but it was a number that we were working with. I'm sure the architect came up with it. It could have been, yeah. And even that seemed to be hype to me. Tear it down and build a new one. What's the square footage of that? Oh man, you're tough.
One of the problems we have with the public procurement, let's see. Yeah, all I can tell you is it's a three bedroom unit. Two floors, three bedrooms, actually three if you want to consider the basement, but I don't think there was a lot of damage in the basement, but that I don't know.
Oh, no, they don't have a basement. That's right. That's Willis. Yeah, there's no basement. It's on Slough. Thank you. So the question, is that the two base bids in the back? I don't know if you saw that, but that's what you were asking for. On which one? Yeah. But you're not including the alternate on this basement? No.
What was the difference between, so on page 244 with the letter, the letter states that the builder's price is $251,440 and then the bid has it at $279. What was the difference? Where did the other roughly $28,000
Was that something that was added on that we don't see? Where did that cost come from? That I don't know. And I don't see it listed here. I see it listed at $279,000. That's including the alternate. Well no, the alternate is only $2,000. What do you recommend?
We're going to have a discussion in a few minutes that because of a grant write-up that we are using
Something that was supposed to be on this agenda didn't get the material to us until today. We need to have a special meeting. The Housing Authority is going to be submitting an application to HUD for a moving to work program. And we need to have a formal vote on that before the end of the month. We were hoping to schedule a special meeting just for that purpose.
We can certainly add this on to that. That would be sometime within the next week. We'd be looking to do that. Is this time sensitive for Gabe in any way? I'm sorry? Is this time sensitive in the next couple weeks? Yes. Yes, it is. It needs to be in both. This? Yeah. That I don't know. Okay. But if there's questions from the board, we can certainly hold off. I don't think that's going to be an issue.
Can I get a motion if anybody wants to table that? Yeah, I'll table E, resolution number 2022-036. All in favor? Aye. All right, great, thank you.
Resolution number 2022-037, consideration of request by executive director to approve certificate of final completion and final payment to MGS Construction Inc. of Denver, Massachusetts for the completion of MHA job number 2108, M1, 10-point apartment, gutters, downfall, fascia, and rake replacement project in the amount of $4,216.19. Move to accept.
Do still, we need a roll call. Yeah. That's money. A roll call. Yes, please. Didn't we already approve those funds? Isn't that just to approve them? Yeah, this is just to approve the... The funds have already been approved. Yeah, funds have already been approved. This is just to approve the certificate of final. The completion. So there's no need for a roll call. All right. The final payment's already been authorized. Yep. Thank you. Learn it. Learn it. I know, geez. Always on top of his game. All right. I was looking for something else. Thank you.
Resolution number 2022-038, consideration of request by Executive Director to approve the Fair Housing Market Plan. Madam Chair? Yes. Jennifer has put this together. She spent a good amount of time in doing so. This is something that she has used DECDs as a guide.
It's my understanding that it is something that they've asked us to do. Kaylene, are you familiar with that? You must be familiar. Yeah, it's a requirement for the new wait list for CHAMP. Yeah. It needs to be uploaded by the end of the month. Yeah. So that CHAMP is the tenant selection process that is used by state-aided housing. So it's a requirement.
I would make a recommendation that the board so vote to approve. Okay. Can I get a motion for resolution? I motion to approve. Second. Second. All in favor? Aye. Aye. Thank you.
Resolution H, resolution number 2022-039, consideration of request by executive director to approve amended language access plan LAP pursuant to GACDPHN 2021-21. 261.
Again, the fine work of Jennifer has updated our language access plan. This one pursuant to a recent notice, a notice that came out at the end of last year that we're required to modify.
The PHN is a public housing notice, that's what that stands for. PHCD will send out notices to us. You'll see it says 2021, so that's 2021, and this is the 21st notice that they had sent out during that year. It just states that the House of Lords will provide language for the residents, right? Yes. That's what I got. Yes.
second only favor all right thank you hi it's a discussion for community preservation committee no I have nothing this except from last
Is it the pleasure of the chair to vote to close that, like you do in other instances, or do we just bypass it? We just bypass it. Okay, I'm good with that. Before we go into executive session, if we could somehow come up with a date for us to go over the rehab
award for the fire damaged unit and also to have the board review and hopefully approve an application for moving to work. Okay. Which is a... I left my phone in the car. I'm sorry? Go ahead, I left my phone in the car with my camera. Which is a HUD program that we would derive great benefits and the residents would also.
And we can do that at any point in time that we have the ability to have a quorum present. Okay. Before the 28th. Before the 28th, right. The submission has to be in before the 28th. Before the 28th of this month. Yes. Okay. I'd actually prefer us not to wait until the 27th to do it.
Are we thinking 4.30 anytime of the day or afternoon? Anytime of the day. Pleasure of the morning. I shouldn't say that to Kayleen because I know there are entities in Lexington that meet at 7 o'clock in the morning. Monday the 25th in the afternoon is difficult for me.
Tuesdays and Thursdays are not great for me. Wednesday the 20th is fine for me. I could definitely do it Wednesday anytime from 6am to 3 o'clock if you want. I can tell you it would be a relatively short meeting.
Wilson, do you have, is this? Oh, I'll make it work. Okay. I don't have my son with me, but I will make it work. Yeah, I'm available anytime during that day, so. That Wednesday, Wednesday usually, you know, I try to, she doesn't have dance, so. I have a meeting from 1 to 2 that day. But other than that, I'm good. For breakfast. What time do you guys get here? We can be here whenever.
I'm out the door at 5.30 usually. Today I was late because I had building pathways at 8 o'clock. I had interviews for building pathways. I left a little later but I don't care. 9 o'clock? 9 o'clock works for me. Wednesday 9 o'clock.
Wednesday, July 20th, 9 o'clock. That's fine. That's good, Losa? Yeah, it's fine. Morning is always good. Wednesday. It's fine. Okay. Monday the 20th, right? Oh, we come today, yeah. First morning meeting at 13 yesterday. Really? Yep. At 9 o'clock? Okay. My husband's going to get the alert on his phone and be like, are you kidding me?
Okay. All right. And Barbara, what will you be sending out to them? I don't have the paperwork yet for the moving to work. I'm waiting for that on Monday. Right. But we'll be sending them information ahead of time. Yes, by Monday. On the moving to work. Yes. Right? Yes, by Monday. Okay.
and also you'll be getting information on Resolution E. Correct. Are you going to give narrative information on what moving to work is? I'm just thinking. Well, probably, depending on how ... I don't remember how lengthy the application was, but we may even give you a copy of the application. Clearly, though, I'm disappointed that that wasn't on this agenda.
and it wasn't because of the fact that we didn't get the, we had a consultant who was doing this work for us and didn't get that back to us in time. Okay. Moving to executive session. Can we move? Okay. Motion to close the regular meeting? Yes. Can I get a motion to close
and go into executive session? Are we going to return? Well, I think you're just going to get a motion just to go into executive session, and then whether or not we are going to announce, whether or not we're going to go return into it. So to adjourn. We will return to regular meeting to adjourn, no? No, there's no reason to return. We can adjourn right from executive session if you announce it ahead of time, and that way Matthew isn't waiting around to come back. Right, that's true.
We had nothing else after that. And so the motion, I believe, if I can recommend, would be one where the board would vote to go into executive session to discuss pending legal matters that are listed, and Barbara can cite those in the motion, where it would be detrimental for the housing authority, to the housing authority's detriment to have a discussion
concerning these matters in open session. Do you know what number that is? What number? Like the reason? I have to think it's that sheet that I gave. I think it's probably... Matthew, thank you for coming. I think it's probably three, maybe three if I'm not mistaken. Do we have to say it or no? Yeah. No, you don't have to say that because what I said was what that is. What Kayleigh's talking about is that in the trainings I have I give out the ten exemptions.
And we just usually just, you can just check that off as far as what it is. Those are the exemptions in the open meeting law and they are numbered 1 to 10.
Who's going to make that motion, Tom? Can I speak? Jeff, I just want to apologize about the chain of command stuff earlier. No problem. I know previously you told me about, you know, the garden stuff and, you know, about the chain of command. And I know that when I decided to advocate for Kate, I just kind of thought that this was a decision made
I want to apologize. Matthew, no reason to apologize. Thank you, but no reason at all. Don't worry about that. Thank you. I know you were waiting for Brianna to reappoint you for a while, and I'm really glad now that you're the vice chair. She's chairman.
We haven't changed yet that's why. Congratulations to the new people on everything. Thank you. Thank you Matthew. Appreciate you. You riding your bike home? To his non-air-conditioned house. Be careful. Yeah. Be careful. It's kind of warm out. It's very warm. Yeah I know. Alright so did we have a... I'm still waiting for that one. Yeah motion. Motion to go into it. So move what Jeff said. We need to have a roll call. Did we get a motion and a second?
I'll move. She'll move. I'll second. Second. Okay. All right. Can I get a roll call? Roll call vote. Yes. Commissioner Genvilla? Yes. Commissioner Foley? Yes. Commissioner Alista? Yes. Commissioner Holy? Yes. Thank you.